# Manuel Ike Lagos

Metro Manila



milagos31@gmail.com



+639565619119



linkedin.com/in/manuel-ike-lagos-webdev



https://milagos09.github.io/portfolio/

## **Summary**

As a Web Developer, I learned different kinds of technology in the frontend such as Bootstrap, jQuery, React.js and a bit of React Native Expo for mobile development. Using the basics of HTML, CSS and Javascript, I was able to create demo games such as Pacman, Flappy Bird, Street Fighter and 1942. At the backend, I am familiar with Node.js and PHP's Codeigniter, Laravel. I was able to create a simple API using Express and hosted in Heroku. And finally for the databases, I have experiences with NoSQL using MongoDB and MySQL for RDBMS. With the technologies mentioned above, I have built two E-Commerce prototypes using MERN and WAMP stack.

For more details of my projects, you can contact me at your most convenient time.

### **Experience**



### **Application Development Analyst**

Accenture in the Philippines

May 2022 - Present (2 months +)



### Engineer

Department of Information and Communications Technology - Philippines

Sep 2018 - May 2022 (3 years 9 months)

Performs project management related responsibilities for the implementation of RA 10929 or the Free Internet Access to Public Places.

- -Developed automated logs extraction using VBA
- -Developed ticketing system using VBA
- -Created web database prototype using NodeJS, MongoDB and hosted on Heroku

#### Student

Zuitt - Coding Bootcamp

Nov 2021 - Mar 2022 (5 months)

Capstone 1: Web based Portfolio

- Created a responsive webpage using Bootstrap
- Created the contents using HTML5
- Styled the webpage using CSS and Bootstrap Components
- Hosted the webpage in GitHub, W3Spaces and Firebase

Capstone 2: E-Commerce API

- Created an API using Node.js
- Created a live server using Express
- Created NoSQL database with MongoDB
- Implemented JSON Web Token for authentication

- Implemented Bcrypt for password encryption
- Hosted the API using Heroku

Capstone 3: E-Commerce Web Application

- Created a Front-end using React
- Used React Hooks
- Used React Bootstrap for the layout and design
- Used the Back-end API from Heroku
- Hosted using Vercel

# Technical Engineer

Planet Cable Inc. (Philippines)
Jul 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year 3 months)

# Service Engineer

Altamedica Incorporated Jun 2014 - May 2017 (3 years)

### Broadcast Technician

Aliw Broadcasting Corporation Oct 2013 - Apr 2014 (7 months)

### **Education**

## Zuitt - Coding Bootcamp

Full Stack Web Developer, Computer Software Engineering 2021 - 2022

A full stack web development bootcamp that focuses on training it students to on learn on demand skills in Full Stack Web Development such as but not limited to HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScipt, NodeJs, MongoDB, Express and React.

# 🙆 Western Visayas College of Science and Technology - Lapaz, Iloilo City

Bachelor of Science - BS, Electronics and Communications Engineering Jun 2007 - Oct 2012

Presently known as Iloilo Science and Technology University.

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

**Electronics Engineer** - Philippine Professional Regulation Commission Issued May 2013 - Expires Dec 2024

#### **Skills**

JavaScript • Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) • Node.js • React.js • Socket.io • MySQL • MongoDB • PHP • jQuery • Java